Register to The E. Robert Schmitz Papers
Yale University Music Library
E. Robert Schmitz Papers
1909-1991
MSS 54
Yale University Music Library
12
(29 boxes)
Music, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials by and about the Franco-American pianist and composer E. Robert Schmitz (1889-1949)
Schmitz, E. Robert (Elie Robert), 1889-1949
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The E. Robert Schmitz Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Schmitz's daughter, Monique Leduc, in 1990.
Arrangement
In 9 series as follows: I. Correspondence. II. Music. III. Photographs. IV. Clippings. V. Programs and Publicity Material. VI. Writings by E. Robert Schmitz and Others. VII. Schmitz School of Piano and Other Music Schools. VIII. Financial and Legal Maters. IX. Scrapbooks.
Scope and Contents
The E. Robert Schmitz Papers contain letters to and from Schmitz and family members, performers, composers, music publishers, and critics. The Papers also hold manuscript scores of music by Schmitz and other twentieth-century composers. The activities of Schmitz and his Pro Musica Society are further documented by: photographs; scrapbooks and clippings; programs and publicity materials; financial records; and information relating to the Schmitz School of Piano.
Biographical / Historical
Elie Robert Schmitz was born in Paris on February 8, 1889. As a boy he sang in a choir at the Church of the Assumption. When he was seventeen, he went on to the Paris Conservatory, where he studied violin, solfège, and ensemble music. His studies were interrupted in 1909, when he toured the United States as an accompanist and coach to the celebrated singers Emma Eames, Maggie Teyte, and Leo Slezak. Schmitz returned to the Conservatory in 1910 and received first prize in piano.
From 1911 to 1914 Schmitz and his wife, Germaine, whom he married on July 1, 1912, directed the Association Musicale Moderne et Artistique. This organization, which included an orchestra, chorus, vocal octet, woodwind ensemble, and string quartet, drew the attention of Camille Saint-Saëns and Vincent D'Indy, among others. In 1914 the Association changed its name to the Association de Concerts Schmitz and grew to include a full orchestra and a 150-member chorus. The Association was responsible for many first performances, including Debussy's Première rhapsodie for clarinet and orchestra, Roussel's Evocations, Le Flem's Crépuscules d'amour, and Milhaud's Suite Symphonique. Schmitz also introduced a series of lecture-recitals entitled "The Musical Geography." These programs concentrated on the music of a particular country, from its folk origins to contemporary composers, with a chamber group performing the music.
Schmitz's concert career flourished; in 1912 he toured Holland and Belgium for three months. He knew all of Debussy's piano works and performed them often. He also coached and accompanied David Devries and Maggie Teyte (who sang the title roles in Pelléas and Mélisande ) for Debussy in their performances of the composer's works.
World War I brought a sudden halt to Schmitz's career. He spent three years at the front, served at the Battle of Verdun, received a shrapnel wound in his left hand, and had eight months of hospitalization for gassing and fatigue. Schmitz's understanding and theory of piano technique originated from his war experience: discussions he had with comrades who were scientists and from his observations of ballistics, mechanics, and acoustics. After the war he went on to study physiology. Schmitz put forth his ideas about piano technique in his book The Capture of Inspiration (1935), which was voted one of the "fifty books of the year" for 1936.
Schmitz reestablished his musical career in the United States after his arrival in New York in 1918. He performed works by the contemporary composers Carpenter, Schoenberg, Ravel, Prokofiev, Milhaud, Honegger, and de Falla. In 1920, Schmitz and Thomas Edison collaborated in making recordings at Edison's New Jersey laboratories. These recordings are now treasured by collectors.
It was also in 1920 that Robert and Germaine Schmitz founded the Franco-American Society, which in 1923 was renamed Pro-Musica, Incorporated. Seeking to promote new music, the Society offered concerts, lecture-recitals, and publications through its forty international chapters. Thanks to the Schmitzes' entrepreneurship, fund-raising, research, and wide musical contacts, the Society was able to sponsor the first American appearances of Ravel, Bartók, and Respighi, as well as concerts and lectures by Hindemith, Schoenberg, Honegger, Milhaud, Roussel, Tansman, Prokofiev and his wife, Lina Llubera, Casella, Bliss, Tailleferre, Schmitt, Kodály, Stravinsky, Webern, Tcherepnin, Toch, Boulanger, Salzedo, Barrère, Eichheim, and the Pro Arte Quartet. Pro-Musica also sent the American composers Marion Bauer, Charles Tomlinson Griffes, and Louis Gruenberg to their Paris chapter and the tenor Roland Hayes to Moscow and Leningrad. They established an International Advisory Board, which included Alban Berg and Egon Wellesz, and in 1923 began a series of International Referendum Concerts. Schmitz toured Europe and the United States performing, lecturing, teaching, and taking care of chapter business. On these tours, Robert and Germaine Schmitz would research local concert history, trying to bring a good balance of old and new in each location.
After Pro-Musica's dissolution in 1936, Schmitz continued to promote new music. He performed, recorded, wrote, edited music, and taught. The E. Robert Schmitz School was established in San Francisco in 1945, and offered a Debussy Prize for pianists. Schmitz died in San Francisco on September 5, 1949.
Antheil, George, 1900-1959; Auric, Georges, 1899-1983; Barraud, Henry, 1900-1997; Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945; Barzin, Leon, 1900-1999; Beli︠a︡ev, V. (Viktor), 1888-1968; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935; Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-1990; Bliss, Arthur, 1891-1975; Bloch, Ernst, 1885-1977; Brailowsky, Alexander, 1896-1976; Brott, Alexander, 1915-2005; Calvocoressi, M. D. (Michel D.), 1877-1944; Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951; Casals, Pablo, 1876-1973; Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947; Champagne, Claude, 1891-1965; Chávez, Carlos, 1899-1978; Chevillard, Camille, 1859-1923; Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1864-1953; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990; Coulthard, Jean, 1908-2000; Damrosch, Walter, 1862-1950; Debussy, Claude, 1862-1918; Defauw, Désiré, 1885-1960; Dello Joio, Norman, 1913-2008; Dubois, Théodore, 1837-1924; Durand, Jacques, 1865-1928; Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva), 1847-1931; Enesco, Georges, 1881-1955; Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946; Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924; Frankenstein, Alfred V. (Alfred Victor), 1906-1981; Garden, Mary, 1874-1967; Gaubert, Philippe, 1879-1941; Gédalge, André, 1856-1926; Golschmann, Vladimir, 1893-1972; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962; Grainger, Percy, 1882-1961; Hanson, Howard, 1896-1981; Harris, Roy, 1898-1979; Harsányi, Tibor, 1898-1954; Haubiel, Charles, 1892-1978; Henriot-Schweitzer, Nicole, 1925-2001; Hoérée, Arthur; Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955; Huré, Jean, 1877-1930; Hurok, Sol, 1888-1974; Indy, Vincent d', 1851-1931; Ives, Charles, 1874-1954; Jean-Aubry, G. (Georges), 1882-1950; Johnson, Lockrem, 1924-1977; Johnson, Thor, 1913-1975; Judson, Arthur, 1881-1975; Kodály, Zoltán, 1882-1967; Korngold, Erich Wolfgang, 1897-1957; Koussevitzky, Serge, 1874-1951; Krenek, Ernst, 1900-1991; Kurtz, Efrem, 1900-1995; Labunski, Felix, 1892-1979; Lawrence, Marjorie; Lévi-Strauss, Claude, 1908-2009; MacDowell, Marian, 1857-1956; MacMillan, Ernest, 1893-1973; Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973; Markevitch, Igor, 1912-1983; Martenot, Maurice, 1898-1980; Massenet, Jules, 1842-1912; Mengelberg, Willem, 1871-1951; Messager, André, 1853-1929; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974; Monteux, Pierre, 1875-1964; Morris, Harold, 1890-1964; Nordoff, Paul, 1909-1977; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985; Pentland, Barbara, 1912-2000; Pierné, Gabriel, 1863-1937; Pijper, Willem, 1894-1947; Pinto, Octavio, 1890-1950; Piston, Walter, 1894-1976; Pons, Lily, 1898-1976; Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953; Rathaus, Karol, 1895-1954; Ravel, Maurice, 1875-1937; Reiner, Fritz, 1888-1963; Reti, Rudolph, 1885-1957; Riegger, Wallingford, 1885-1961; Rieti, Vittorio, 1898-1994; Rodzinski, Artur, 1892-1958; Ropartz, J. Guy (Joseph Guy), 1864-1955; Rosenthal, Manuel, 1904-2003; Roussel, Albert, 1869-1937; Rudhyar, Dane, 1895-1985; Saint-Saëns, Camille, 1835-1921; Salzedo, Carlos, 1885-1961; Schmitt, Florent, 1870-1958; Schmitz, E. Robert (Elie Robert), 1889-1949; Schmitz, Germaine, 1890-1959; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951; Sevitzky, Fabien, 1891-1967; Slonimsky, Nicolas, 1894-1995; Sowerby, Leo, 1895-1968; Steinberg, William, 1899-1978; Stevens, Halsey, 1908-1989; Still, William Grant, 1895-1978; Stock, Frederick, 1872-1942; Stokowski, Leopold, 1882-1977; Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971; Szymanowski, Karol, 1882-1937; Tailleferre, Germaine, 1892-1983; Talma, Louise, 1906-1996; Tansman, Alexandre, 1897-1986; Tcherepnin, Alexander, 1899-1977; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989; Tibbett, Lawrence, 1896-1960; Toch, Ernst, 1887-1964; Turner, Godfrey, 1913-1948; Varèse, Edgard, 1883-1965; Walter, Bruno, 1876-1962; Wolff, Albert, 1884-1970; Franco-American Musical Society; Pro Musica (Society)
- Correspondence, Series I; 4.2 linear feet (10 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The correspondence is divided into two subseries: A. General; and B. Requests for Information from Monique Leduc. It includes letters both to and from Robert and Germaine Schmitz, Monique Leduc, and Joyce Kozloff. The correspondence is arranged alphabetically by sender, except for entries broken down by correspondence to and from Schmitz and others.
  A pencil note has been made on the correspondence which was originally found with the disassembled scrapbooks. Enclosures are noted, and there are cross-references to main entries and to related materials in other series.
  - General Correspondence, I.A
    - A. Dandelot & Fils
      General
      See: Dandelot, A.
    - A. Durand & Fils Editeurs
      See: Durand, Jacques; and VIII.A. FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIALS. A. Durand & Fils Editeurs
    - Adam, Helen D.
      See: Carnegie Hall
    - Adams, Jean Coulthard (Mrs. Donald)
      See: Coulthard, Jean
    - Adams, John T.
      See: Music League of America, Inc.
    - Adaskin, Harry, 1901-, 1948 Jan. 20; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      To Monique Leduc
    - Aeolian American Corporation (Box 1, Folder 2)
      1919-1929. -- 17 items from Aeolian
      1920-1929. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      1920 Feb. 13. -- 1 item from C.H. Pfeiffer to Lyon Healy (copy)
      [ca. 1920 Mar.?]. -- 1 item from A. Frances Hanson to Pfeiffer (copy)
      Also laid in: 4 contracts (1919-1929); 4 royalty statements (1927-1929); 1 business card belonging to A.J. Lehmkuhl "Duo-Art"; 1 clipping (ca. 1921 Nov. 10); and 1 sheet with jottings by E. Robert Schmitz (1924?)
    - Aeolian Company
      See: Aeolian American Corporation
    - Ainsworth, Helen
      See: National Concert and Artists Corporation
    - Allen, Marjorie (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1948 June 1. -- 1 item from Allen
      1948 June 12. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Alphonse, Prince de Bavière, 1912 July 15; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 1)
      Photograph enclosed
      With: telegram from Louis Ferdinand, Prince de Bavière, 1912 May 18
    - American Arts Foundation. Academy of Music, postmarked 1934 Sep. 21; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Music Center
      See: Turner, Godfrey
    - American Piano Company
    - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers (Box 1, Folder 3)
      1946 Nov. 4-18. -- 2 items from ASCAP
      1946 Oct.-Nov. -- 2 items from Monique Leduc
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.4. North American Prize
    - Amherst College, 1939 Feb. 14; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AMPICO
    - AM-RUS Edition
      See: Leeds Music Corporation
    - Anguita, Julio Esteban, 1930 Nov. 12; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 3)
      From E. Robert Schmitz to Anguita
    - Antheil, George, 1900-1959, 1945 Dec. 26; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Armitage, Merle, 1893-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      1950 Jan. 20-30. -- 4 items from Armitage
      1950 Jan. 27. -- 1 item from Monique Leduc
    - Arnaud, Claude (Box 1, Folder 5)
      1946 June 21. -- 1 item from Arnaud
      1946 Aug. 1. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Associated Music Publishers, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1940-1946. -- 5 items from AMPI
      1946 Sep. 13. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      Also laid in: 5 contracts (1941-1943) and 17 royalty statements (1941-1950)
    - Associated Musicians of Greater New York. Local 802
      See: Radio Corporation of America. RCA Victor Division
    - Association Artistique de Marseille, 1923 Apr. 4; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Asociación Musical de Filipinas (Box 1, Folder 7)
      1930-1931. -- 2 items from the Asociación to E. Robert Schmitz
      1930-1931. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to the Asociación
    - Atwood Bookbinding Corporation
      See: Carl Fischer, Inc.
    - Auric, Georges, 1899-, 1922 no month 15; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      The month is either Jan., Oct., or Nov.
    - Baldwin Piano Company (Box 1, Folder 9)
      1930-1932. -- 27 items from Baldwin to E. Robert Schmitz
      1930-1937. -- 27 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Baldwin
    - Bamman, Catharine A., 1919 Mar.-May; 4 items. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barclay, John, no year Jan. 30; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Barnett, Joseph
    - Baron, Maurice (Box 1, Folder 11)
      1946 May-Dec. -- 4 items from Baron
      1946-1947. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Bill laid in (1946 Nov. 26)
    - Barraud, Henry, 1900- (Box 1, Folder 12)
      1946-1948. -- 6 items from Barraud to E. Robert Schmitz
      1946 Apr.-May. -- 2 items from Janet Goossens to E. Robert Schmitz concerning Barraud
      1947 Aug.-Nov. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: Radiodiffusion Française
    - Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      1924-1930. -- 6 items from Bartók to E. Robert Schmitz
      1924-1930. -- 12 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Bartók
      1931 Apr. -- 1 item from Germaine Schmitz to Bartók
      1 item Manuscript list of above correspondence, with synopses in English
      1943 Jan. 10. -- 1 item Clipping
    - Barzin, Leon (Box 1, Folder 14)
      1934 Jan. 16. -- 1 item from Barzin
      1932-1934. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      Enclosure
    - Beaudet, Jean Marie (Box 1, Folder 15)
      1947-1948. -- 5 items from Beaudet
      1947-1948. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: Canadian Broadcasting Corporation
    - Beaux Arts
      See: France. Ministère de l'Instruction Publique et des Beaux Arts
    - Beckridge, R.
      See: Baldwin Piano Company
    - Behymer, L.E.
      See: Bogue Laberge Concert Management, Inc.
    - Beliaev, V. (Viktor), 1888-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      1926-1929. -- 10 items from Beliaev to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
      Includes a negative of a typed letter signed, and a typed letter signed (photocopy) [for original of photocopy see: Monteux, Pierre, 1922 Feb. 18]
      1926-1927. -- 5 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Beliaev
      [1926?] Jul.26. -- 1 item from Germaine Schmitz (Ely Jade) to Beliaev
    - Berg, Alban, 1885-1935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      1925 Apr. 10. -- 1 item from Berg to E. Robert Schmitz (Translation laid in)
      1924 May 25. -- 1 item from Berg and Wellesz
      1924-1925. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Berg
    - Berger, Arthur V., 1912-
      See: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL FOR PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Bernstein, Leonard, 1918-, 1946 Nov. 15-16; 2 items. (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Signed by Helen Coates, Secretary to Mr. Bernstein
    - Bertrand, Raoul (Box 1, Folder 18)
      1946 June 21. -- 1 item from Betrand
      1946 June 19. -- 1 item from E. Robert Schmitz
      See also: VII.SCHMITZ SCHOOL FOR PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Binental, Leopold, 1930-1931; 3 items. (Box 1, Folder 19)
      From E. Robert Schmitz to Binental
    - Blasco Ibáñez, Vicente, 1867-1928, 1920 Jan. 12; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bliss, Arthur, Sir, 1891-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      [1927?]-1944. -- 6 items from Bliss to E. Robert Schmitz
      1925-1928. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Bliss
    - Bloch, Ernst, 1885-1977, and Marguerite, 1940-1947; 14 items. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Brochure laid in
    - Bocande, ?, 1919 Feb. 18; 1 item. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bogue, Lucy D.
      See: Bogue Laberge Concert Management, Inc.; and Concerts "Pro Arte"
    - Bogue Laberge Concert Management, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 24)
      1923-1936. -- 11 items from Bogue Laberge
      Includes photocopy - for original see also: Tansman, Alexandre, and typed letter (copy) from Bogue Laberge to Mr. Miller of Thomas A. Edison, Inc.
      1933 Aug. 15. -- 1 item from Laberge to Paul Wittgenstein
      [1933] July 11. -- 1 copy of letter to Bogue Laberge from L.E. Behymer
      1933 July 13. -- 1 copy of letter to Bogue Laberge from Arthur Gaines
      1933 July 25. -- 1 copy of letter to Bogue Laberge from V. Golschmann and Cecile Leger
      1924 Jan. 21. -- 1 copy of letter to Bogue Laberge from F. White Neumann
      1922-1936. -- 12 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Bogue Laberge
      3 sheets with notes by E. Robert Schmitz and 4 sheets listing expenses laid in
      See also: Honegger, Arthur; and Horner-Witte Concert Bureau, Inc.
    - Bond von Nederlandsch-Indische Kunstringen (Box 2, Folder 25)
      1928-1931. -- 8 items Bond... to E. Robert Schmitz
      1928-1931. -- 6 items E. Robert Schmitz to Bond
      3 postal receipts laid in
    - Bonnet, Henri, 1888-1978 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      1944-1946. -- 2 items from Bonnet to E. Robert Schmitz
      Includes telegram (photocopy) [for original see: Schoenberg, Arnold, 1926 May 3]
      1946 June-Sep. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Bonnet
      See also: France Forever; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF MUSIC AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.5. Debussy Prize
    - Bottenheim, S. A. M. (Salomon Adriaan Maria), 1880-1957 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      1930 Nov. 6. -- 1 item from Bottenheim to Podoli
      1930 Oct.-Nov. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Bottenheim
      See also: Concerts Populaires
    - Bottorff, O.O.
    - Bouchet, Louis
    - Boyer, Charles, 1899-1978, 1946 Jan. 15; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Braille Musician, 1948 Jan.-Mar.; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Brailowsky, Alexander, 1896-1976, 1947 Feb. 24; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Brewster, Robert
    - Bricken, Carl, 1945 Dec. 18; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Brott, Alexander, 1915- (Box 2, Folder 32)
      1947 Apr. -- 2 items from Brott to Monique Leduc
      1947 Apr.-Nov. -- 5 items from Monique Leduc to Brott
    - Brouzet, A.
      See: France. Consulat Général (N.Y.)
    - Brown, Marion (Box 2, Folder 33)
      1949 Nov. 2. -- 1 item from Brown to Germaine Schmitz
      1949 Nov. 15. -- 1 item from Germaine Schmitz to Brown
    - Browne, Walter and Ione, 1945-1949; 4 items. (Box 2, Folder 34)
      From E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF MUSIC AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.3. Trust Fund
    - Browning, Mortimer, 1947 Aug. 18; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 35)
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF MUSIC AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.4. North American Prize
    - Brussel, Robert (Box 2, Folder 35)
      1927 Oct.-Nov. -- 2 items from Brussel to Bernard Laberge (copies)
      1927 May-Nov. -- 3 items from Laberge to Brussel
      See also: France. Ministère de l'Instruction Publique et des Beaux Arts
    - Byrne, F.H.B.
    - California. Department of Education. Division of Public School Administration. Bureau of Readjustment Education, 1949 Mar.-Apr.; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 36)
      See also: VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.2. Summer Session
    - Calvocoressi, M.D. (Michel D.), 1877-1944 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      1923-1924. -- 5 items from Calvocoressi to E. Robert Schmitz
      1923-1925. -- 4 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Calvocoressi
    - Cambern, Carroll G.
    - Campanini, Cleofonte
      See: Chicago Opera Association
    - Canadian Broadcasting Corporation, 1941-1947; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 38)
      See also: Beaudet, Jean Marie
    - Carl Fischer, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 39-41)
      1937-1975. -- 60 items from Carl Fischer (2 enclosures)
      1937-1975. -- 36 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Monique Leduc
      1937 Nov. 5. -- 1 item from Major Press, Inc. to Carl Fischer
      1937 Nov. 5. -- 1 item from Atwood Bookbinding Corp. to Carl Fischer
      1942 Nov. 7. -- 1 item from Cambern to Hauser
      1942 Nov. 9. -- 1 item from Cambern to Robert Brewster, Producer, Kraft Music Hall, c/o J. Walter Thompson
      Also laid in: 7 contracts (1937-1948); 22 royalty statements (1939-1983); 2 bills (1948 Aug.-Sep.); and 2 assigned Canadian copyrights
      See also: Free Library of Philadelphia. Edwin A. Fischer Music Collection; and VII. SCHMITZ SCHOOL OF PIANO AND OTHER SCHOOLS. A.4. North American Prize
    - Carnegie Hall, 1941 May 13; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 42)
      "List for mailing the announcements Carnegie Hall recital" laid in
      See also: National Concert and Artists Corporation; and B. Requests for Information from Monique Leduc. Francesconi, Gino
    - Carpenter, John Alden, 1876-1951 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      1919-1945. -- 15 items from Carpenter to E. Robert Schmitz
      Copy of typed letter from Damrosch to Carpenter laid in
      1926-1927. -- 8 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Carpenter (Includes notes)
    - Carrel, Alexis, 1873-1944, 1920 Jan. 12; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 44)
      Photocopy
    - Carter, C.L.
    - Cartier, Ambassador
      See: Concerts "Pro Arte"
    - Casals, Pablo, 1876-1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      1930 Apr. 12. -- 1 item from Casals to E. Robert Schmitz
      1920 Feb.-June. -- 2 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Casals
    - Casella, Alfredo, 1883-1947 (Box 2; 29, Folder 46; 2)
      1922-1930. -- 8 items from Casella to E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz
      1922-1930. -- 10 items from E. Robert Schmitz to Casella
      1926 May. -- 1 item from Casella for Associated Press (copy)
    - Cassell, Marion, 1948 May 7; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 47)
      From Monique Leduc
    - Caston, Saul, 1946 Jan. 9; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Cbojnaelej?, 1927 Mar. 2; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Chabaury, Raphael, 1946 Sep. 13; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 47)
      See also: Debussy Prize
    - Chabrier, André and Mrs., no date; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Champagne, Claude, 1891-1955, 1946 Nov. 7; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Chausson, Jeanne (Mrs. Ernest), no date; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Chávez, Carlos, 1899- (Box 2, Folder 50)
      1927-1954. -- 5 items from Chávez to E. Robert Schmitz
      1927-1954. -- 3 items from E. Robert Schmitz and Germaine Schmitz to Chávez
    - Chejnacki, Mr., 1927 Jan. 15; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Chevillard, Camille, p.m. 1917?; 1 item. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Chicago Opera Association, 1918 Sep. 17; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 51)
      2 copies of contract
    - Child, Emily
      See: Pro-Musica (Minneapolis Chapter)
    - [Chinaglia], Detta?, 1927 Feb.-Mar.; 2 items. (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Citkowitz, Israel